African-American related sheet music, and sheet music written by African-Americans, 1851-1974 M1433
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
African-American related sheet music and sheet music written by African-Americans
1851-1974
M1433
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
10.5 Linear feet (648 pieces; 7 flat boxes)
The collection consists of sheet music written by African-American writers and sheet music published by African-American publishers between 1851 and 1974.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2004.
Biographical/Historical note
The collection consists of sheet music written by African-American writers and sheet music published by African-American publishers between 1851 and 1974.
Scope and Contents note
The collection is arranged in two series: Series I. Sheet music written by African-Americans and Series II. Sheet music about African-American themes. Within each series, the material is arranged alphabetically by title.
African Americans in popular culture--Songs and music.; African Americans--Music; African Americans--Social life and customs.; Gospel music--United States.; Lithographs.; Music--African-American; Piano music.; Popular music.; Ragtime music.; Sheet music.; Songs with piano.
- Series I. Sheet music written by African-American writers, published by African-American publishers
  - 12th Street Rag, Euday L. Bowman, Andy Razaf, 1944 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - 5 Original Compositions, Clarence "Pine Top" Smith, 1941 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - 5 Jazz Piano Solos, Art Tatum, 1944 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - 5 Piano Solos, Mary Lou Williams, various, 1941 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - 52nd Street Theme, Thelonius Monk, 1948 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Ain't-Cha' Glad?, Andy Razaf, Thomas Waller, 1933 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Ain't Misbehavin', Andy Razaf, Thomas Waller, Harry Brooks, 1929 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Alabama Hop, Jos. H. Barrett, 1904 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - All Coons Look Alike to Me, Ernest Hogan, 1896 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Arkansas Blues, Anton Lada, Spencer Williams, 1921 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Art Tatum Improvisations, Art Tatum, 1939 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Art Tatum Improvisations No.2, Art Tatum, 1946 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - At the Ball That's All, J. Leubrie Hill, 1913 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Ballin' the Jack Fox-Trot, Chris Smith, James Reese Europe, 1914 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Basin Street Blues, Spencer Williams, 1933 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Beale Street Blues, W.C. Handy, no date (Flat-box 1, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Beans! Beans!! Beans!!!, Elmer Bowman, Chris Smith, 1912 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Be-Bop Boogie, Benny Carter, 1948 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Believe It, Beloved, George Whiting, Nat Schwartz, J.C. Johnson, 1934 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Believe It, Beloved, George Whiting, Nat Schwartz, J.C. Johnson, 1934 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Black and Blue, Andy Razaf, Thomas Waller, Harry Brooks, 1929 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Blame It on the Blues, Chas. L. Cooke, 1914 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Blues in My Heart, King Carter, Irving Mills, 1931 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Bon Bon Buddy; Bandana Land, Alex Rogers, Will Marion Cook, 1907 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Bon Bon Buddy, Alex Rogers, Will Marion Cook, 1907 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Boogie Woogie, Clarence "Pine Top" Smith, 1939 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - Brother Bill, Louis Armstrong, 1942 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Bugle Call Rag, Jack Pettis, Irving Mills, Elmer Schoebel, Arr. "Fats" Waller, 1934 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - Bye Bye My Eva Bye Bye, Chris Smith, Harry Brown, 1905 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - Candy Store Blues, Herb Jeffries, Nick Castle, Eddie Beal, 1948 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Caravan, Duke Ellington, Juan Tizol, Irving Mills, 1937 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - Carry Me Back to Old Virginny, James Bland, 1890 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - Casey Jones Went Down On the Robert E. Lee, Marvin Lee, Clarence Jones, 1912 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - Castle House Rag, James Reese Europe, 1914 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - Cataract Rag, Robert Hampton, 1914 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Christopher Columbus, Andy Razaf, Leon Berry, 1936 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Clementine, Henry Creamer, Harry Warren, 1927 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - Come Out Dinah on the Green, Bob Cole, J.R. Johnson, J.W. Johnson, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - Come Right In, Sit Right Down, Make Yourself At Home, Bob White, Alfred Anderson, Will H. Dixon, 1909 (Flat-box 1, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - Cosey Rag, The, Shelton Brooks, 1911 (Flat-box 1, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Cotton Fields, Huddie Ledbetter, 1962 (Flat-box 1, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Count Basie Boogie Woogie Blues, various, 1944 (Flat-box 1, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - Cross Over the Bridge, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, 1954 (Flat-box 1, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - Cryin' Mood, Andy Razaf, Chick Webb, 1937 (Flat-box 1, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - Darktown Strutters' Ball, The, Shelton Brooks, 1917 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - Dat's Harmony, Grant Clarke, Bert Williams, 1911 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Dat's Ma Honey Sho's Yo' Born, Joe Jordan, 1912 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - Dat's Music to Me, Chris Smith, Harry Brown, 1907 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - Dawning, Abner Silver, Maceo Pinkard, 1927 (Flat-box 1, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - Days of a Short While Ago, E.P. Womack, arr. Harry P. Guy, 1920 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Dear Old Moonlight, Henry S. Creamer, Tom. Lemonier, 1909 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Deep River, arr. H.T. Burleigh, 1917 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11, Item 3)
  - Dirty Dozen, The, Clarence M. Jones, Jack Frost, 1917 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11, Item 4)
  - Dirty Dozen, The, Clarence M. Jones, Jack Frost, 1917 (Flat-box 1, Folder 11, Item 5)
  - Do Nothin' Til You Hear From Me, Bob Russell, Duke Ellington, 1943 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12, Item 1)
  - Down in Poverty Row, Gussie L. Davis, Arthur Trevelyan, 1896 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12, Item 2)
  - Down in Sunny Alabama, James Burrel, Jas. T. Brymn, 1901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12, Item 3)
  - Echoes From the Snowball Club, Harry P. Guy, 1898 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12, Item 4)
  - Fatal Wedding, The, Gussie L. Davis, 1898 (Flat-box 1, Folder 12, Item 5)
  - Flirtation Waltz, The, R. Heywood, arr. Winifred Atwell, 1953 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Frenchy-Koo, Billy Baskette, Maceo Pinkard, 1919 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Friendless Blues, W.C. Handy, 1935 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Fun and Fancy Free, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, 1947 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Gee Baby, Ain't I Good to You, Don Redman, Andy Razaf, 1944 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Get Your Money's Worth, Irving Jones, 1897 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Ghost of a Coon, Bert Williams, George Walker, 1900 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Go, Chain de Lion Down, J. Rosamond Johnson, 1935 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Go 'Long, Mule, Henry Creamer, Robert King, 1924 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Good-Bye Alexander, Good-Bye Honey Boy, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1918 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Good-Bye Dear Moon, Joe Jordan, 1913 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Items 5)
  - Good Man is Hard to Find, Eddie Green, 1918 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Good Morning Carrie, R.C. Mcpherson, Chris Smith, Elmer Bowman, 1901 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Goodnight, Irene, Huddie Ledbetter, John Lomax, 1901 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Gotta Feelin' For You; Holloywood Revue of 1929, Jo' Trent, Louis Alter (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Grace and Beauty, James Scott, 1909 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Green Pastures Spiritual, arr. Hall Johnson, 1930 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Gypsy Blues, Noble Sissle, Eubie Blake, 1921 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Harvard Blues, George Frazier, Tab Smith, Count Basie, Arr. Charlie Hathaway, 1942 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - He's a Son of the South, Andy Razaf, Joe Davis, Reginald Foresythe, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Hesitating Blues, The, W.C. Handy, 1915 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - He's Up Against the Real Thing Now, Edward Furber, Bert A. Williams, 1898 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - I Ain't Got Nothin' But the Blues, Don George, Duke Ellington, 1944 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - I Can't Get Up the Nerve to Kiss You, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, 1947 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - I Can't Let 'Em Suffer, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1918 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - I Can See Clearly Now, Johnny Nash, 1972 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - I Can't Think of Nothing in the Wide Wide World But You, Bob Cole, J. Rosamond Johnson, 1907 (Flat-box 2, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - I Didn't Know About You, Bob Russel, Duke Ellington, 1944 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - I Don't See Me in Your Eyes Anymore, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, 1949 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - I Don't Want to Set the World on Fire, Eddie Seiler, Sol Marcus, Eddie Durham, Bennie Benjamin, 1941 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - If I Could be With You, Henry Creamer, Jimmy Johnson, 1926 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - If I Only Could Blot Out the Past, Gussie L. Davis, 1896 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - If It Ain't Love, Andy Razaf, Donald Redman, Thomas Waller, 1932 (Flat-box 2, Folder 6, Item 6)
  - If We Never Meet Again, Horace Gerlach, Louis Armstrong, 1936 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - If You'll Be My Eve, J. Weldon Johnson, J. Rosamond Johnson, 1907 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - If You Love Your Baby, Make Goo Goo Eyes, Bert Williams, George Walker, 1900 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - If You're Such a Great Start, Why Don't You Shine, Irving Jones, 1903 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - I Got to Lie Down, arr. Hall Johnson, 1951 (Flat-box 2, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - I Just Roll Along Havin' My Ups and Downs, Jo' Trent, Peter DeRose, 1927 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - I Let a Song Go Out Of My Heart, Irving Mills, Henry Nemo, John Redmond, Duke Ellington, 1938 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - I Lost My Sugar in Salt Lake City, Leon Rene, Johnny Lange, 1942 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - I'm Beginning to See the Light, Harry James, Duke Ellington, Johnny Hodges, Don George (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - I'm Goin' to Live Anyhow Till I Die, Shepard N. Edmonds, 1901 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - I'm Just Wild About Harry, Noble Sissle, Eubie Blake, 1921 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 6)
  - I Never Knew I could Love Anybody, Tom Pitts, Ray Eagan, Roy K. Marsh, 1920 (Flat-box 2, Folder 8, Item 7)
  - In Search of a Husband, Clarence Jones, 1914 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - In the Morning by the Bright Light, James A. Bland, 1879 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - I See a Million People, Robert Sour, Una Mae Carlisle, 1941 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - It Don't Mean a Thing, Irving Mills, Duke Ellington, 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - I Thought I Heard Somebody Calling Me, Al Johns, 1898 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - It's Right Here For You, Marion Dickerson, Alex Belledna, 1920 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 6)
  - It's Wonderful, Mitchell Parish, Stuff Smith, 1938 (Flat-box 2, Folder 9, Item 7)
  - I've Got a Feeling I'm Falling, Billy Rose, Harry Link, Thos. Waller, 1929 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - I've Got Chicken on the Brain, Elmer Bowman, Al Johns, arr. Will Tyers, 1899 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Ivy (Cling to Me), Alex Rogers, Isham Jones, Jimmy Johnson, 1922 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - I Want Jesus to Walk With Me, Jean Stor, 1933 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - I Wish I Could Shimmy Like My Sister Kate, A. J. Piron, 1922 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - I Wonder Where My Easy Rider's Gone, Shelton Brooks, 1913 (Flat-box 2, Folder 10, Item 6)
  - "Jazz" Dance, The, W. Benton Overstreet, 1917 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Jazz-Me Blues, The, Tom Delaney, 1921 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Jean, Frank L. Stanton, H.T. Burleigh, 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 3)
  - Jitterbug Waltz, The, Thomas "Fats" Waller, 1942 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 4)
  - Jo-Anne, Abner Silver, Maceo Pinkard, Joe Ward, 1928 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 5)
  - Josephine, Henry Creamer, Ray Brown, Henry Ackley, 1924 (Flat-box 2, Folder 11, Item 6)
  - Joshua Fit de Battle ob Jericho, arr. H.T. Burleigh, 1935 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 1)
  - Jumpin' Jive, The, Cab Calloway, Frank Froeba, Jack Palmer, 1939 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 2)
  - Just a Crazy Song, Chick Smith, Spencer Williams, 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 3)
  - Just to Behold His Face and Touch Me, Lord Jesus, Lucie E. Campbell, 1945 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 4)
  - King Porter Stomp, Ferd "Jelly Roll" Morton, arr. Dick Hyman, 1974 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 5)
  - Lady Sings the Blues, Billie Holiday, Herbie Nichols, 1972 (Flat-box 2, Folder 12, Item 6)
  - La Rumba, J. Tim. Brymn, 1913 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - Let It Alone, Alex Rogers, Bert A. Williams, 1906 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 2)
  - Lila, Archie Gottler, Chas. Tobias, Maceo Pinkard, 1928 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 3)
  - Lina Ma Lady, Carroll Fleming, Sid. L. Perrin, 1900 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 4)
  - Linda, Charlie Tobias, Jo' Trent, Peter DeRose, 1931 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 5)
  - Little Bo Be-Bop, Erroll Garner, 1948 (Flat-box 2, Folder 13, Item 6)
  - Little Gypsy Maid, The, Harry B. Smith, Cecil Mack, Will Marion Cook, 1902 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 1)
  - Little Mother Of Mine, Walter H. Brown, H.T. Burleigh, 1917 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 2)
  - Liza Jane, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1918 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 3)
  - Louisiana Lize, Bob Cole, J.W. Johnson, J.R. Johnson, 1899 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 4)
  - Louisville Blues, Bob Ricketts, Mike Jackson, 1922 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 5)
  - Love Will Find a Way, Noble Sissle, Eubie Blake, 1921 (Flat-box 2, Folder 14, Item 6)
  - Lovie Joe, Will Marion Cook, Joe Jordan, 1910 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15, Item 1)
  - Loving You the Way I Do, J ack Scholl, Will Morrissey, Eubie Blake, 1930 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15, Item 2)
  - Maiden With the Dreamy Eyes, James Weldon Johnson, Bob Cole, 1901 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15, Item 3)
  - Mammy O' Mine, Win. Tracey, Maceo Pinkard, 1919 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15, Item 4)
  - Manda, Noble Sissle, Eubie Blake, 1924 (Flat-box 2, Folder 15, Item 5)
  - Maniac's Ball, Gene Gifford, arr. Alex Hill, 1933 (Flat-box 3, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Maple Leaf Rag, Scott Joplin, 1909 (Flat-box 3, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Ma Ragtime Baby, Chas. Stone, Fred S. Stone, 1899 (Flat-box 3, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Mary Jane, Andy Razaf, J. Russel Robinson, 1931 (Flat-box 3, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Memories Of You, Andy Razaf, Eubie Blake, 1930 (Flat-box 3, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Memphis Blues, The, W.C. Handy, 1931 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Mexico; Humpty Dumpty, Bob Cole, James Weldon Johnson, 1904 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Minnie the Moocher, Cab Calloway, Irving Mills, Clarence Gaskill, 1931 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Missouri Blues, Harry Brown, 1919 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Mister Johnson, Ben R. Harney, 1896 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Mistreatin' Daddy, Porter Grainger, 1923 (Flat-box 3, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Moan, You Moaners!, Spencer Williams, 1931 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Molasses Candy, Eddie Leonard, J. Leubrie Hill, 1910 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Muddy Water, Jo' Trent, Peter DeRose, Harry Richman, 1926 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - My Creole Sue, Gussie L. Davis, 1898 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - My Dinah, Sidney L. Perrin, 1900 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Nightfall, Benny Carter, 1939 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Nobody, Alex Rogers, Bert A. Williams, 1905 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Nobody Knows de Trouble I've Seen, Clarence Cameron White, 1920 (Flat-box 3, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Nobody's Looking But de Owl An' De Moon, J.W. Johnson, Bob Cole, J.R. Johnson, no date (Flat-box 3, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - O Death Where is Thy Sting, Clarence A. Stout, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Oh! Didn't He Ramble, Will Handy, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Oh Say! Can I See You To-Night, Henry Creamer, Joe Schuster, Leon Flatow, 1925 (Flat-box 3, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Oh! What It Seemed To Be, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, Frankie Carle, 1945 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Old Flag Never Touched the Ground, The, J.W. Johnson, Bob Cole, J. Rosamond Johnson, 1917 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Old Folks Rag, Wilbur C. Sweatman, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - One and Two and Three and Four Rock-a-Bye, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1919 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Ornithology, Charlie Parker, Benny Harris, 1948 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Pauline Waltz, Clarence M. Jones, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Pianissimo, Bennie Bejamin, George Weiss, 1947 (Flat-box 3, Folder 5, Item 7)
  - Please Let Me Sleep, R.C. McPherson, James. T. Brymn, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Pretty Baby, Gus Kahn, Tony Jackson, Egbert Van Alstyne, 1916 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - Pretty Eyed Baby, Mary Lou Williams, William Johnson, 1951 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Princeton Tiger, A, Gerald Burke, Scott Joplin, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - Prosperity Rag, James Scott, 1930 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - Railroad Blues, Haven Gillespie, Howard Washington, C. Luckeyth Roberts, 1920 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 6)
  - Razzle Dazzle, Willard Thompson, arr. J. Rosamond Johnson, 1934 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 7)
  - Returned, Will Marion Cook, Paul Laurence Dunbar, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 6, Item 8)
  - Rhythm and Romance, Geo. Whiting, Nat Schwartz, J.C. Johnson, 1935 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Rock Me In the Cradle Of Love, J. Leubrie Hill, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - Rollin' Down the River, R. Stanley Adams, Thomas Waller, 1930 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - Rufe Johnson's Harmony Band, Shelton Brooks, Maurice Abrahams, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - Rumors are Flying, Bennie Benjamin, George Weiss, 1946 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - Runnin' Wild, Joe Grey, Leo Wood, A. Harrington Gibbs, 1922 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 6)
  - Shoulder to Weep On, A, Bennie Benjamin, Geo. Weiss, Patricia Peale, 1952 (Flat-box 3, Folder 7, Item 7)
  - Silks and Rags, Fred S. Stone, 1901 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Since Bill Bailey Came Back Home, Billy Johnson, Seymour Further, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Sing Again That Sweet Refrain, Gussie L. Davis, 1937 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - Sleepy Hollow, Harold G. Frost, Lemuel Fowler, F. Henri Klickmann, 1920 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - Snake Hips, Spencer Williams, 1923 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - Somebody Lied, Jeff T. Branen, Evans Lloyd, Bert A. Williams, 1907 (Flat-box 3, Folder 8, Item 6)
  - Someday Sweetheart, Benj. Spikes, John Spikes, 1924 (Flat-box 3, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Some of These Days, Shelton Brooks, 1910 (Flat-box 3, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Some of These Days, Shelton Brooks, 1922 (Flat-box 3, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - Someone's Rocking My Dreamboat, Leon Rene, Emerson Scott, Otis Rene, 1941 (Flat-box 3, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - Springtime of Love, James Scott, 1919 (Flat-box 3, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - St. Louis Blues; Blackbirds of 1928, W.C. Handy (Flat-box 3, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - St. Louis Blues, W.C. Handy, 1942 (Flat-box 3, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Strut Miss Lizzie, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1921 (Flat-box 3, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - Summertime is the Time For Me, Sheppard Edmonds, 1910 (Flat-box 3, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - Sunflower Slow Drag, Scott Joplin, Scott Hayden, 1901 (Flat-box 3, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - Susianna, Spencer Williams, 1929 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Sweet Man, Roy Turk, Maceo Pinkard, 1925 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Sweet 'n Pretty, Henry Creamer, J. Turner Layton, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 3)
  - Take Your Clothes And Go, Irving Jones, arr. Will H. Tyers, 1897 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 4)
  - Tall Timber, Andy Razaf, Thomas Waller, 1933 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 5)
  - Thanks For the Lobster, Clarence Jones, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 11, Item 6)
  - That Baseball Rag, Dave Wolff, Clarence Jones, 1913 (Flat-box 3, Folder 12, Item 1)
  - There'll be Some Changes Made, W. Benton Overstreet, 1923 (Flat-box 3, Folder 12, Item 2)
  - There'll Come a Time, Shelton Brooks, 1911 (Flat-box 3, Folder 12, Item 3)
  - There's a Big Cry-Baby In the Moon, James Burris, Chris Smith, 1909 (Flat-box 3, Folder 12, Item 4)
  - They Led My Lord Away, arr. James Elmo Dorsey, 1947 (Flat-box 3, Folder 12, Item 5)
  - Things Ain't What They Used To Be, Ted Persons, Mercer Ellington, 1943 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - Thunderin', Wonderin', Robert MacGimsey, 1933 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 2)
  - Tishomingo Blues, Spencer Williams, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 3)
  - To-Night I Shall Sleep, Duke Ellington, Mercer Ellington, Irving Gordon, 1943 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 4)
  - Under the Bamboo Tree, Bob Cole, 1902 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 5)
  - Vampire, The, Earl Jones, Gene Buck, Bert A. Williams, 1914 (Flat-box 3, Folder 13, Item 6)
  - Voo-Doo Man, The, Bert Williams, George Walker, 1901 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 1)
  - Wake Up! Chill'un Wake Up!, Jo' Trent, Willard Robison, 1929 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 2)
  - When Aunt Dinah's Daughter Hannah Bangs On That Piano, James (Slap) White, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 3)
  - When the Lights Go On Again, Eddie Seiler, Sol Marcus, Bennie Benjamin, 1942 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 4)
  - While Ole Mammie Jinnie's Caperin' On the Green, Shepard N. Edmonds, 1903 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 5)
  - Whistling Blues, Joe Diamond, Jack Barnett, Saxi Holtsworth, 1920 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 6)
  - Who Knows?, Paul Laurence Dunbar, Ernest R. Ball, 1909 (Flat-box 3, Folder 14, Item 7)
  - Why Do Fools Fall In Love, Frank Lymon, George Goldner, 1956 (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 1)
  - Williams' Colored Singers, various, no date (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 2)
  - Will "Ya" Huh?, Roy Turk, Jack Smith, Maceo Pinkard, 1926 (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 3)
  - Yama Yama Blues, Spencer Williams, Clarence Williams, 1919 (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 4)
  - Yes She Do- No She Don't, Jo' Trent, Peter DeRose, no date (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 5)
  - You Can Have It, I Don't Want It, Mary Hill, Clarence Williams, Armand J. Piron, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 15, Item 6)
  - You're All the World to Me, Arthur J. Lamb, Clarence M. Jones, 1915 (Flat-box 3, Folder 16, Item 1)
  - Your Red Wagon, Don Raye, Gene de Paul, Richard M. Jones, 1947 (Flat-box 3, Folder 16, Item 2)
  - You're Gwine to Get Somethin' What You Don't Expect, Bert Williams, 1910 (Flat-box 3, Folder 16, Item 3)
  - You're in the Right Church But the Wrong Pew, C ecil Mack, Chris Smith, 1908 (Flat-box 3, Folder 16, Item 4)
  - You're Some Pretty Doll, Clarence Williams, 1918 (Flat-box 3, Folder 16, Item 5)
- Series II: Sheet Music with African-American themes
  - 11th Hour Melody, King Palmer, Carl Sigman, 1956 (Flat-box 4, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Across the Alley From the Alamo, Joe Greene, 1947 (Flat-box 4, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - After My Laughter Came Tears, Roy Turk, Charles Tobias, 1928 (Flat-box 4, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Ah Wed 300 Pounds, Speed Langworthy, 1929 (Flat-box 4, Folder 1, Item 4)